Guide to the University Historical Material records, 1821-2012 RG0031
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Copies of University Charters and Recorder's Receipts, 07/25/1871-07/14/1910; 1904-1905; RG0002 Series 53; George Washington University. Board of Trustees; District of Columbia. Office of the Recorder of Deeds; Columbian College in the District of Columbia; 0.25 Linear Feet 1 slim document box
  - Two Certified Copies of the Articles of Incorporation of the Columbian College, and Recorder's Receipts, 07/23/1904-02/10/1910; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    This Charter changed the name of Columbian University to the George Washington University. It also established the Columbian College as the body controlling all academic undergraduate institutions within the University.
  - Certified Copy of the Certificate of Change of Name of the Columbian University to The George Washington University (1904), 02/11/1910; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Recorder's Receipts, Surrender of Franchise, November 30, 1904, 11/30/1904; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Typescript of Act to Incorporate the Columbian College in the District of Columbia (1821), and Supplemental Acts (1832-1905), circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Certified Copy of the Articles of Incorporation of Washington College of Engineering and Recorder's Receipts, November 14, 1905, 11/14/1905; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Under the provisions of the March 3, 1905 supplemental Act of Congress amending the charter of The George Washington University, this established the Washington College of Engineering, a semi-independent undergraduate college of the University.
  - Signed Board of Trustees Resolution (May 6, 1909), and Recorder's Receipts for Certificate of Corporation Seal (1908) and Certificate of Increase of Membership (1909), 02/21/1908-05/29/1909; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    This resolution by the George Washington University Board of Trustees increased the number of Trustees and authorized GW alumni to nominate each year two from their number to serve three-year terms as Trustees.
  - Two Copies of the Certificate of Incorporation of the National College of Pharmacy, 07/14/1910; RG0002 Series 53 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    The National College of Pharmacy was taken over by the George Washington University as an affiliated college.